Teimur Gasanov

Full-stack Developer

I am a purposeful full-stack developer worked mostly with Javascript, Python and Go. I am experienced in setting up environments with Docker and creating CI/CD using Jenkins and Travis CI. While a novice, for now, in this particular field, I am enthusiastic about using machine learning with Python. I am the type of developer who is constantly self-learning and improving himself.

Experience

Personal Info

Phone:

+996550010726

E-mail:

teymurgg321@gmail.com

Website:

https://teimurjan,github.io

Hard skills

Javascript - expert

NodeJS - expert

ReactJS - expert

Python - expert

Go - advanced

Docker - expert

Jenkins, Travis Cl

- intermediate

PostgreSQL - advanced

MySQL - advanced

Soft Skills

Interpersonal skills

Collaboration

Problem solving

Other

TDD

BDD

Agile

Design Patterns

Computer Science

Attractor Software LLC

Full-stack Developer,

October 2016 - May 2018

- Work with the team using Agile and Scrum methodologies
- Designed and built APIs using Python/JavaScript
- Made an existing localized application multilingual
- Migrated users from a big web application into a separate microservice
- · Wrote unit and acceptance tests
- Created UI components of various levels of difficulty
- Optimized an existing front-end application in order to increase the loading speed
- Created a browser extension for scrapping, analyzing, and representing the data
- Worked in variously sized teams of two, four, and eight developers

Stratact GmbH

Front-end Developer,

June 2018 - January 2019

- Created a fully responsive, custom Bootstrap theme using styled components
- Made different CSS animation from simple transitions to complex GIF-based animations
- · Optimized the startup performance
- Provided support for Internet Explorer 11 (IE 11)
- · Set up full international support
- · Covered 95% with unit and snapshot tests

EvanX

Front-end Developer,

June 2018 - January 2019

- · Created an immutable architecture for a complex tree-like text editor
- · Designed customized DraftJS editor
- Set up front-end ready for any real-time back-end
- · Optimized rendering performance of the text editor app
- Wrote bash scripts for setting up the environment for MacOS

Clubhouse

Front-end Developer,

February 2019 - Present

- Implemented new landing pages using Gatsby and Prismic
- Reduced usage of Typescript's any types
- Set up autogenerating Typescript types from GraphQL schemas
- Solved the tasks in the team of designers, developers, product and engineering managers
- Designed new visual and interactive components

Education

Ala-Too International University

Computer Science Department,

September 2015 - June 2019

- · Got strong mathematical background
- Received basic knowledge of Algorithms, Data Structures, Databases, Networking, and Robotics

Achievements

Kyrgyzstan Subregional Programming Contest

Entered top 10 and got the certificate of achievement.

Openline Hackathon

Created the crowdfunding platform and entered top 5.

Google Developers Group 2018 Bishkek

Had a talk about the optimization of React applications.

PyCon 2018 Kyrgyzstan

Had a talk about data visualization using Python.

Google Developers Group 2018 Almaty

Had a talk about the UI documentation in React.